<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BioLoco Research</title>
    <link>https://ivalab.github.io/BioLoco/public/</link>
    <description>Recent content on BioLoco Research</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ivalab.github.io/BioLoco/public/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>IVALab BioLocomotion Robots</title>
      <link>https://ivalab.github.io/BioLoco/public/robots/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivalab.github.io/BioLoco/public/robots/</guid>
      <description>So far we have one truly functional robot, Snakey.
We have a once functional robot, Sally the Supermander, who apparently was used to scavenge motors from. We are in the process of bringing her back to her original glory.
And we have a small quadruped that needs lots of love to get functional again, Kitty the Robocat (aka Crookshanks).
Off-and-on we are working towards creating a small Gorilla-bot and some other fun biologically-inspired robots that could be used to showcase the mathematics and algorithms we&amp;rsquo;ve derived.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Snake-Like Robot-Ground Interactions.</title>
      <link>https://ivalab.github.io/BioLoco/public/research/scales/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivalab.github.io/BioLoco/public/research/scales/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; To reproduce the locomotion modalities associated to snakes
requires achieving the same robot-ground contact force interactions.
Following the biomechanics literature we designed a robosnake scale
chassis to put on each of Snakey&amp;rsquo;s joints. Doing so improved locomotion
stability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling Planar Snake Movement.</title>
      <link>https://ivalab.github.io/BioLoco/public/research/modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivalab.github.io/BioLoco/public/research/modeling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt; When the correct representation for modeling snake movement
is chosen, then deriving equations of motion for snake movement on a flat
plane is fairly easy.  Furthermore, one overall dynamic model provides a
unified approach to modeling many different gaits.  So far, we have
modeled rectilinear locomotion, lateral undulation, and sidewinding.
A turn-in-place gait is currently under study.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rectilinear Snake Motion.</title>
      <link>https://ivalab.github.io/BioLoco/public/research/rectilinear/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivalab.github.io/BioLoco/public/research/rectilinear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; Rectilinear locomotion is different from but analgous to
caterpillar locomotion. The body undulates vertically only to move
forward. Curving the body leads to turning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sally the Supermander.</title>
      <link>https://ivalab.github.io/BioLoco/public/research/sally/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivalab.github.io/BioLoco/public/research/sally/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; The objective of this senior design project was to design
and build a robotic salamander, then to realize some basic locomotion
gait for it. Naturally, motor technology being what it is, this robot is
bigger than your typical salamander.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snakey SLAM-Nav</title>
      <link>https://ivalab.github.io/BioLoco/public/research/autonav/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivalab.github.io/BioLoco/public/research/autonav/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; Our lab also researches SLAM (Simultaneous Localization
and Mapping) and Auotnomous Navigation.  We thought it would be fun to
combine these to see what we could get.  Using a wireless camera, we
gave it a shot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IVALab BioLocomotion Research</title>
      <link>https://ivalab.github.io/BioLoco/public/bioloco/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivalab.github.io/BioLoco/public/bioloco/</guid>
      <description>So far, we have been studying snake locomotion with the intent to figure out how to perform planning, trajectory synthesis, and feedback control for this class of bio-inspired robots. We got the theory mostly worked out for flat planar surface, and hope that we can experimentally verify the mathematics. So far, we&amp;rsquo;ve got rectilinear motion down, and are going to take care of sidewinding next. Lateral undulation is a bit trickier since the motion dynamics are a bit more complex.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>